{
    "id": "c2335d532f6941b5bfe7e4152e691770",
    "title": "Prepositions And Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She couldn’t qualify for the race ……………………….. having trained very hard.",
            "description": "In spite of is a preposition. It can be followed by an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "in spite of",
                "however",
                "although"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "71bbf147c3dd4977a64045a63394bc7b"
        },
        {
            "question": "He couldn’t pass the exam ………………………… he worked very hard.",
            "description": "Although is a conjunction. It is followed by a clause. In spite of and despite are prepositions. ",
            "answers": [
                "in spite of",
                "although",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8c60c68c02a4466bb60ab4465482f2e0"
        },
        {
            "question": "She sat …………………….. me across the table.",
            "description": "In front of does not mean ‘across a table from.’ That idea is expressed with opposite or facing.",
            "answers": [
                "facing",
                "in front of",
                "opposite"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fed57c7529c34fd3b7471083a67fb8c4"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… did he start going out with her than she fell in love with another guy.",
            "description": "Note the pattern ‘no sooner…than’.",
            "answers": [
                "As soon as",
                "No sooner",
                "Hardly"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9c173461c1ca43fa8c0ce1150c62bc4d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I was hardly inside the house …………………….. the lights went out.",
            "description": "Hardly can be followed by when or before.",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "before",
                "than"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "48491f34229c4df1b554f026274f818a"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. had I closed my eyes when the dog started barking.",
            "description": "Both hardly and scarcely can be followed by when or before.",
            "answers": [
                "No sooner",
                "As soon as",
                "Scarcely",
                "Hardly"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "892cc7a011df44bf829d85838432aff6"
        },
        {
            "question": "She has been a go-getter ……………………… her childhood.",
            "description": "From is possible with a present perfect tense in expressions that mean ‘right from the start’.",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8d2c84e10603425891b76269526f0054"
        },
        {
            "question": "The shop was open ……………………………. the morning.",
            "description": "Since is usually used with a present perfect tense. From is used with simple tenses. ",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "from",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d5deec68dcc34695a6c3b071e9481d3a"
        },
        {
            "question": "We had to cancel the picnic ……………………………….. bad weather.",
            "description": "Due to and owing to both mean because of.",
            "answers": [
                "due to",
                "owing to",
                "because of",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "649bfd50ae194da3a413409b2195e80b"
        },
        {
            "question": "He doesn’t care …………………………. his appearance.",
            "description": "If you care about something, it interests or worries you.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "for",
                "about"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "047186edb5114a3ca62802da6ea67cab"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ………………………….. the Harvard School of Business.",
            "description": "We use at to say where people study.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "at",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c09a01c56b3e47c597c31ebb41505a79"
        },
        {
            "question": "I won’t be leaving ………………………… Friday.",
            "description": "Not until means the same as not before.",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "before",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d0d97b5506dc4bbba8ab0c6103e683c6"
        }
    ]
}